<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://christt105.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Elit3D</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/elit3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/elit3d/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Elit3D" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elit3D is a tile-based map editor in 3D. Composed of several layers of tiles and 3D objects, it allows you to export the maps in different formats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Godosters</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Godosters" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Godosters is a Pokémon-style game engine and project, currently developed in Godot 4. The project has evolved through several iterations and technologies, including C++, Unity, and Godot 3. It aims to provide a flexible base for creating monster-taming games, with features like a custom map system, actor/event logic, shaders, and more. For a detailed history and devlogs, check the related blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Witcher: A Bard's Tale</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post The Witcher: A Bard's Tale" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Witcher: A Bard’s Tale is a cooperative action game developed by 37 students from the Bachelor’s Degree in Video Game Design and Development at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC). This project was created over the course of three months as part of the subject “Project 3,” with the goal of simulating the workflow of a real indie studio. Developed entirely using our own custom engine, the team was divided into design, programming, and art departments, working together to bring a complete game experience to life. I focused on programming, rotating between gameplay and engine development throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Final Fantasy: Mystery World</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/finalfantasymysteryworld/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/finalfantasymysteryworld/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Final Fantasy: Mystery World" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy: Mystery World is a dungeon crawler RPG with micro-turn-based combat, where players follow the main story branch to rescue their kidnapped friend from the clutches of a mysterious monster in the Final Fantasy universe. Along the journey, players must also help the villagers trapped in this strange world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took on the role of Team Lead, coordinating the team&amp;rsquo;s workflow, managing task distribution, and ensuring smooth collaboration. In addition to leading the team, I also contributed significantly as a core programmer, working on game systems, combat logic, and overall structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whisp Engine</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/whispengine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/whispengine/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Whisp Engine" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whisp Engine is a custom 3D game engine developed from scratch using OpenGL and SDL, featuring a basic Lua scripting system and a Unity-inspired entity-component architecture. It was created over the course of three months as part of the Game Engines subject in the third year of the Videogame Development degree at CITM-UPC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sprite Ordering and Camera Culling</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/spriteorderingculling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/spriteorderingculling/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Sprite Ordering and Camera Culling" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project is part of the second-year course &lt;em&gt;Project 2&lt;/em&gt; at CITM-UPC, supervised by lecturer Ricard Pillosu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research focuses on optimizing 2D games by implementing &lt;strong&gt;camera culling&lt;/strong&gt;, which means only rendering sprites visible inside the camera viewport, improving performance. It also explores &lt;strong&gt;sprite ordering techniques&lt;/strong&gt; to create a convincing sense of depth in &lt;strong&gt;top-down&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;isometric&lt;/strong&gt; games. The project includes integration of the &lt;strong&gt;Tiled map editor&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;SDL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance analysis using &lt;strong&gt;Brofiler&lt;/strong&gt; can be found in the repository, demonstrating the impact of camera culling on rendering efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/Result_Gif_5370883700662292685.gif"
	width="770"
	height="600"
	loading="lazy"
	
		alt="gif with result of sprite sorting"
	
	
		class="gallery-image" 
		data-flex-grow="128"
		data-flex-basis="308px"
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pokétch</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/poketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/poketch/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Pokétch" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pokétch Unity is a recreation of the Pokétch device from Pokémon Platinum, developed in Unity with all the original functionalities plus new features. This project is focused on delivering a smooth experience on Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Andro Dunos</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/androdunos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/androdunos/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Andro Dunos" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andro Dunos Remake is a side-scrolling shoot &amp;rsquo;em up inspired by the classic arcade game Andro Dunos. It was my first game project, developed entirely from scratch in C++ using SDL. Built as a team effort, I took the role of lead programmer, responsible for core systems such as rendering, input, collision, and enemy behavior. The game includes multiple levels, enemy waves, and basic power-up mechanics, aiming to replicate the fast-paced feel of early 90s arcade shooters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boxing AR</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/boxingar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/boxingar/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Boxing AR" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Control a boxing robot and achieve the RoboBoxing glory!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empty Universe</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/emptyuniverse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/emptyuniverse/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Empty Universe" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empty Universe is an exhaustic adventure where you will have to defend the ship of enemies. You will have three types of astronauts in your control. Each astronaut has his own job in order to get all ship needs covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survive five days and nights to win. Don&amp;rsquo;t let the enemies kill your astronauts and manage your resources well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fishing Trash</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/fishingtrash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/fishingtrash/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Fishing Trash" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A GameJam with &amp;lsquo;sea&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;garbage&amp;rsquo; as the theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Godot Pixel Water Reflection Shader</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godotwaterreflection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godotwaterreflection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Godot Pixel Water Reflection Shader" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shader that simulates the Pokémon Gen 3 water reflection effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is ready to use with sprite sheets textures. You can modify the movement options and the color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/animation1_9493276995836067974.gif"
	width="950"
	height="536"
	loading="lazy"
	
		alt="Use of the shader"
	
	
		class="gallery-image" 
		data-flex-grow="177"
		data-flex-basis="425px"
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kitty Lee</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/kittylee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/kittylee/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Kitty Lee" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a small project made by two videogame students of UPC CITM from Terrassa called Kitty Lee. Kitty Lee a side-scrolling platformer game about exploring a mysterious underground place. Our Hero is a skilled warrior cat with a red band and his name is Lee. There is two different levels: while the first one is based on the player exploration on the cave, the second one represents the exit of this dangerous place where the player has to escape from. Lee will have to reach the end of the levels avoiding enemies which will start chasing him. Besides, Lee can collect coins that he finds into the levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Media Cover Recap</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/mediacoverrecap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/mediacoverrecap/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Media Cover Recap" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collage generator from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.notion.com/templates/media-tracker-en" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
 &gt;Notion Media Tracker template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum Translation</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/pokemonfollowingrenegadeplatinum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/pokemonfollowingrenegadeplatinum/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum Translation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project provides translation patches for the ROM hacks Pokémon Following Platinum and Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum, making them fully playable in Spanish.
It was developed using Python together with the tool thenewpoketext, which allows extraction, editing, and reinsertion of game text into the ROMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Following Platinum, the translation combines the original Spanish text from Pokémon Platinum with newly translated content introduced by the hack.
For Following Renegade Platinum, it builds upon Drakyem’s Spanish translation of Renegade Platinum, adding all the additional content from Following Platinum as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tileset Grid Test Creator</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/tilesetgridtestcreator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/tilesetgridtestcreator/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Tileset Grid Test Creator" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;An online tool that creates tilesets or grids with different sizes and colors. Made with Godot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>