<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pokémon on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/tags/pok%C3%A9mon/</link><description>Recent content in Pokémon on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://christt105.github.io/tags/pok%C3%A9mon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Godosters</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Godosters" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Godosters is a Pokémon-style game engine and project, currently developed in Godot 4. The project has evolved through several iterations and technologies, including C++, Unity, and Godot 3. It aims to provide a flexible base for creating monster-taming games, with features like a custom map system, actor/event logic, shaders, and more. For a detailed history and devlogs, check the related blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pokétch</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/poketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/poketch/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Pokétch" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pokétch Unity is a recreation of the Pokétch device from Pokémon Platinum, developed in Unity with all the original functionalities plus new features. This project is focused on delivering a smooth experience on Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum Translation</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/pokemonfollowingrenegadeplatinum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/pokemonfollowingrenegadeplatinum/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum Translation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project provides translation patches for the ROM hacks Pokémon Following Platinum and Pokémon Following Renegade Platinum, making them fully playable in Spanish.
It was developed using Python together with the tool thenewpoketext, which allows extraction, editing, and reinsertion of game text into the ROMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Following Platinum, the translation combines the original Spanish text from Pokémon Platinum with newly translated content introduced by the hack.
For Following Renegade Platinum, it builds upon Drakyem’s Spanish translation of Renegade Platinum, adding all the additional content from Following Platinum as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>