<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Game on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/tags/game/</link><description>Recent content in Game on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://christt105.github.io/tags/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Witcher: A Bard's Tale</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post The Witcher: A Bard's Tale" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Witcher: A Bard’s Tale is a cooperative action game developed by 37 students from the Bachelor’s Degree in Video Game Design and Development at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC). This project was created over the course of three months as part of the subject “Project 3,” with the goal of simulating the workflow of a real indie studio. Developed entirely using our own custom engine, the team was divided into design, programming, and art departments, working together to bring a complete game experience to life. I focused on programming, rotating between gameplay and engine development throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Final Fantasy: Mystery World</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/finalfantasymysteryworld/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/finalfantasymysteryworld/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Final Fantasy: Mystery World" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy: Mystery World is a dungeon crawler RPG with micro-turn-based combat, where players follow the main story branch to rescue their kidnapped friend from the clutches of a mysterious monster in the Final Fantasy universe. Along the journey, players must also help the villagers trapped in this strange world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took on the role of Team Lead, coordinating the team&amp;rsquo;s workflow, managing task distribution, and ensuring smooth collaboration. In addition to leading the team, I also contributed significantly as a core programmer, working on game systems, combat logic, and overall structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Andro Dunos</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/androdunos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/androdunos/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Andro Dunos" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andro Dunos Remake is a side-scrolling shoot &amp;rsquo;em up inspired by the classic arcade game Andro Dunos. It was my first game project, developed entirely from scratch in C++ using SDL. Built as a team effort, I took the role of lead programmer, responsible for core systems such as rendering, input, collision, and enemy behavior. The game includes multiple levels, enemy waves, and basic power-up mechanics, aiming to replicate the fast-paced feel of early 90s arcade shooters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boxing AR</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/boxingar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/boxingar/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Boxing AR" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Control a boxing robot and achieve the RoboBoxing glory!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empty Universe</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/emptyuniverse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/emptyuniverse/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Empty Universe" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empty Universe is an exhaustic adventure where you will have to defend the ship of enemies. You will have three types of astronauts in your control. Each astronaut has his own job in order to get all ship needs covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survive five days and nights to win. Don&amp;rsquo;t let the enemies kill your astronauts and manage your resources well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fishing Trash</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/fishingtrash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/fishingtrash/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Fishing Trash" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A GameJam with &amp;lsquo;sea&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;garbage&amp;rsquo; as the theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kitty Lee</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/kittylee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/kittylee/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Kitty Lee" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a small project made by two videogame students of UPC CITM from Terrassa called Kitty Lee. Kitty Lee a side-scrolling platformer game about exploring a mysterious underground place. Our Hero is a skilled warrior cat with a red band and his name is Lee. There is two different levels: while the first one is based on the player exploration on the cave, the second one represents the exit of this dangerous place where the player has to escape from. Lee will have to reach the end of the levels avoiding enemies which will start chasing him. Besides, Lee can collect coins that he finds into the levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>