<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engine on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/tags/engine/</link><description>Recent content in Engine on Christian Martínez De La Rosa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://christt105.github.io/tags/engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Godosters</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/godosters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Godosters" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Godosters is a Pokémon-style game engine and project, currently developed in Godot 4. The project has evolved through several iterations and technologies, including C++, Unity, and Godot 3. It aims to provide a flexible base for creating monster-taming games, with features like a custom map system, actor/event logic, shaders, and more. For a detailed history and devlogs, check the related blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Witcher: A Bard's Tale</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/thewitcher/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post The Witcher: A Bard's Tale" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Witcher: A Bard’s Tale is a cooperative action game developed by 37 students from the Bachelor’s Degree in Video Game Design and Development at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC). This project was created over the course of three months as part of the subject “Project 3,” with the goal of simulating the workflow of a real indie studio. Developed entirely using our own custom engine, the team was divided into design, programming, and art departments, working together to bring a complete game experience to life. I focused on programming, rotating between gameplay and engine development throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whisp Engine</title><link>https://christt105.github.io/projects/whispengine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christt105.github.io/projects/whispengine/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://christt105.github.io/" alt="Featured image of post Whisp Engine" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whisp Engine is a custom 3D game engine developed from scratch using OpenGL and SDL, featuring a basic Lua scripting system and a Unity-inspired entity-component architecture. It was created over the course of three months as part of the Game Engines subject in the third year of the Videogame Development degree at CITM-UPC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>